Guide to the Richard Courant Papers MC 150
New York University Archives
- Series II: Files from the Office of Richard Courant
  - Subseries A: General Files
    - (Drs.) Johnson & Kolstad (RC Conversation), 1952 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Johnson, L.B.--U.S. Presidential Campaign (1964), 1964-1965 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Walter J. Inc., 1968 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Joint Symposium on Partial Differential Equations Aug. 19-30 1963 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Jorgens, Konrad, 1960-1965 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Jubilé Scientifique de Monsieur Gaston Julia, 1962 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - "K" Misc., 1941-1955 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - "K" Misc., 1957-1971 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Kac, Marc, 1961-1964 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Kaemffert, Waldemar, 1941-1942 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Kallman, H.P., 1959 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Kamke, Prof. [Erich], 1949-1950 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Kansas, University of, 1952-1958 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Keller, Joseph B., "Lectures on Mechanics of Continuous Media", 1949-1950 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Kelly, Mervin J., 1953-1959 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Kelly, Mervin J., 1961, undated (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Keppel, E.P., 1936-1937 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Key, Samuel Witt, "A Convergence Investigation of the Direct Stiffness Method" (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Key, Samuel Witt, "A Convergence Investigation of the Direct Stiffness Method" (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Kilgore, Sen. H.M., 1943-1955 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Killian, J.R., 1954-1960 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Kim, Nak Kwan, 1948-1955 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - King, Robert W., 1942-1949 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Kinzel, Augustus B., 1951-1960 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Kinzel, Augustus B., 1961-1968 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Klapper, Paul (President of Queens College), 1937-1938 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Klemin, Alexander, 1948 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Kline, Morris, 1956-1960 (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Kline, Morris, 1961-1968 (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Knebelman, M.S., 1940-1948 (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Knopp, Konrad, 1949-1954 (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Koopmans, Tjalling, 1964-1965 (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Koppenfels, Werner--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1929 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Koryavov, Pavel (see "Russian Mathematician"), 1963-1968 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Konig, Robert, 1947-1948 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Kothe, Gottfried, 1946-1958 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Kottler, Friedrich, 1921-1922, 1938, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Krahn, Edgar--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1925 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Kramer, Edna E., 1940-1944 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Kramers, H.A., 1948-1955 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Kramers, H.A.--"The Behavior of Micromolecules in Inhomogeneous Flow", 1946 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Kramers PDE (1 of 2), 1939-1940 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Kramers PDE (2 of 2), 1939-1940 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Kranzer, Herbert, 1961-1967 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Kronsbein, John, 1948-1950 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Kuratowski, K., 1960 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - "L" Misc., 1945-1960 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - "L" Misc., 1961-1967 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Ladenberg, Rudolph, 1938-1949 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Landau, Marianne, 1946-1960 (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Lane, Frank, 1953-1954 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Lange, Luise--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1925 (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Lange, Luise, 1939-1942 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Lanier, Lyle H., 1950 (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - Laporte, Otto, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 23)
    - von Laue, Max, 1948-1954 (Box 57, Folder 24)
    - Lavrentyev family (see "Russian Mathematicians"), 1963-1964 (Box 57, Folder 25)
    - Lawrence Radiation Laboratory (RC consulting), 1963-1964 (Box 57, Folder 26)
    - Lax, Anneli, 1950-1959 (Box 57, Folder 27)
    - Lax, Anneli, 1961-1966 (Box 57, Folder 28)
    - Lax, Henry, 1951-1953 (Box 57, Folder 29)
    - Lax, Peter, 1944-1968 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Lax, Peter, 1950-1960 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Lax, Peter--"Translation Invariant Spaces", undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Lax, Peter--"The Wave Equation in Exterior Domains", undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Lax, Peter and Courant--"On Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations with Two Independent Variables", undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Lectures Given in April 1969 (1 of 3) (Box 58, Folder 6)
      Contains materials from the International Conference on Functional Analysis and Related Topics
    - Lectures Given in April 1969 (2 of 3) (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Lectures Given in April 1969 (3 of 3) (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Lectures--Göttingen (1 of 2), undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Lectures--Göttingen (2 of 2), undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Lectures--New York 1932 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Leitner, Alfred, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Lekarski, Iwan--General Files, 1940 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Letters, [1939] (Box 58, Folder 14)
      Contains full issue of New York Times Magazine from October 22, 1939 (copy)
    - Letters (extra copies) (1 of 2), 1965 November-1966 June (Box 59, Folder 1)
      Correspondence related to Courant's publishing, Novosibirsk conference, death of James Franck and travel
    - Letters (extra copies) (2 of 2), 1965 November-1966 June (Box 59, Folder 2)
      Correspondence related to the academic journal Mathematische Annalen, Soviet Academy of Sciences, and the death of Alfred Sloan
    - Letters (extra copies), 1966 July-1966 December (Box 59, Folder 3)
      Corresondence about Mathematische Annalen, meetings, speaking engagements, misc.
    - Letters (extra copies), 1967 January-1967 October (Box 59, Folder 4)
      Corresponce re: Mathematische Annalen, 1967 Gallatin Awards dinner, misc, meetings and travel
    - Letters on Math Subjects--not answered, 1957-1958, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Letters--extra copies misc., 1954, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Letters-misc. and reprints, 1959-1964 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Leray, Jean, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Levi, F.W., 1950 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Levia-Civita, Tulio [and Libera], 1938-1958 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Lewy, Hans, 1946-1951 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Lewy, Hans, 1950-1960 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Lewy, Hans--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1927 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Li, Ta, 1933-1948 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Liason Office NY Branch, 1944-1945 (Box 59, Folder 15)
      Material from Office of Emergency Management
    - Liason Office, Washington DC, 1944 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      Material from National Defense Research Committee
    - Library Administration, 1938-1939 (Box 59, Folder 17)
      Lectures on the Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable
    - Lichtenstein, Stephanie, 1949-1951 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Lie's Theory, Invariant Differential Equations, undated (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Lieber, L.R. and H.G. (Galois Inst. of Math.), 1937-1942 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Life [Magazine], 1945 April (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Lighthill, M.J., 1951-1959 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Lin, C.C., 1946 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Lindegren, Carl C., 1947 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Lindsay, John, 1966-1967 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Lockheed Missiles and Space Company, 1947 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Lorentz, G.G.--"Minimalfolgen und das Dirichletsche Prinzip", undated (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Lorentz, G.G.--"Uber das Dirichletsche Prinzip", undated (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, 1952-1953 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, 1955 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, 1952-1960 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Lowan, Arnold, 1935-1950 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Luchins, Edith H. and Abraham S., 1961-1970 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Ludwig, Donald, 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Ludwig, Donald, 1961-1969 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Ludwig, Donald, undated (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Ludwig, Donald and Courant--"Distributions as Tools for the Generalization of Riemann's Formula for Hyperbolic Differential Equations", undated (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Luneburg, Rudolph, 1936-1949 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Matters [includes corrections for Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II, misc. corrrespondence], 1943-1963 (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - McDonald, James G.--Letter of Resignation, 1935 (Box 60, Folder 23)
      McDonald served as High Commissioner for Refugees (Jewish and Other) Coming from Germany
    - McShane, E.J., 1949-1959 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - McShane, E.J., 1961-1966 (Box 60, Folder 25)
    - Meder, Albert E. Jr. (American Mathematical Society), 1961-1963 (Box 60, Folder 26)
    - Memoranda to Staff [NYU Applied Mathematics Group], 1943-1944 (Box 60, Folder 27)
    - Memorial Address, 1972-1973 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Menger, Karl, 1938-1944 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Outline Notes, 1950 October 30 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Chapter 1, 1950-1951 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Lecture Course Summer 1943 NYU (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Misprints, 1953-1965 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Chapters 1-2 [access copy, German edition, 1937] (Box 61, Folder 7)
      General Note
      Box 61, Folder 6-9 and Box 62 Folders 1-2 contain a preservation photocopy of Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II. The original copy is too fragile to handle.
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Chapters 3-4 [access copy, German edition, 1937] (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Chapter 5 [access copy, German edition, 1937] (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Chapter 6 [access copy, German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Chapter 7, Index [access copy, German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II annotations from copy 2 [German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 3)
      This folder contains copies of the annotated pages from additional copies of Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II found in the collection. The originals are too fragile to handle.
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II annotations from copy 3, Chapters 1-2 [German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II annotations from copy 3, Chapters 3-4 [German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II annotations from copy 3, Chapter 5 [German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II annotations from copy 3, Chapters 6-7 [German edition, 1937] (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Intro-Chapter 1, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 1)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Chapter 2, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 2)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Chapter 3, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 3)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Chapter 4, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 4)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Chapter 5, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 5)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Chapter 6, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 6)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 1, Chapter 7-Index, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 7)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Intro-Chapter 1 (incomplete), 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 8)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Chapter 2 (incomplete), 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 9)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Chapter 3, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 10)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Chapter 4, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 11)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Chapter 5, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 12)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Chapter 6, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 13)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 2, Chapter 7, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 14)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 1, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 15)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 2, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 16)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 3 (incomplete), 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 17)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 4, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 18)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 5, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 19)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 6, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 20)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 3, Chapter 7 (incomplete), 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 21)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 4 p. 113-128, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 22)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 4 p. 177-208, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 23)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 4 p. 289-368, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 24)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 4 p. 369-448, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 25)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 4 p. 449-512, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 26)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Copy 4 p. 513-544, covers, 1937 (Box 62b, Folder 27)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Appendix to Chapter 6--Ideal Functions or Distributions (1 of 2), 1961 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Appendix to Chapter 6--Ideal Functions or Distributions (2 of 2), 1961 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Constructions--Illustrations, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Corrections (2nd edition), 1963-1964, undated (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--(some) corrections and index taken care of, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Drawings to Chapter V, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Figures, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Galley Distribution List/Interscience enclosure slips, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II illustrations (old-not used), undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Non-Linear Hyperbolic Equations, undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--References misc., 1956, 1961, undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II--Translation from Edmund H. Brown and Karl T. Hecht, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Meyer, Richard E., 1955 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Midterm Paper, 1919 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Microfilms, 1945 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Microfilms Inc. List of Current Foreign Periodicals Available on Microfilm
    - Milgram, A.N., 1951-1952 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Minck, P.M., 1961 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - "Minimal Surfaces Spanning Closed Manifolds" by Courant and N. Davids, undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Minkowsky's Two Theorems, undated (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Minorsky, N., 1946 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1966 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      Contains materials and correspondence on origins of IMS, establishment of Warren Weaver Hall, CIMS name change
    - Miscellaneous, 1959-1971 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      Includes CIMS Governing Council minutes, materials and correspondence on CIMS directorship
    - Miscellaneous, 1966-1970 (Box 63, Folder 18)
      Includes correspondence to/from biographer Constance Reid, Fritz John, material related to event honoring Polish Professor Tadeusz Ważewski
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence from Other Universities, 1961-1964 (Box 63, Folder 19)
      Includes requests for speaking engagements
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence from Other Universities, 1964-1971 (Box 63, Folder 20)
      Includes correspondence to/from Constance Reid re: her Hilbert biography as well as letters about the manuscript and nomination of Mina Rees for University of Chicago Alumni Association award
    - Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1941, 1954-1956 (Box 63, Folder 21)
      Contains notes on a business trip Courant took to DC, NYU administrative memo, introductory remarks from 1941 memo to National Science Foundation
    - Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1958, undated (Box 63, Folder 22)
      Contains memos on IMS and AEC Computing Center
    - Miscellaneous Questions and Answers, undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Mitchell, Lawrence C., 1960 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Model Basin--Minorsky, 1942-1944 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Modern Mathematics for the Engineer--correspondence, 1953-1957 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Montgomery, Deane, 1961-1962 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Morawetz, Cathleen--interview with Courant, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Morawetz, Cathleen (and Herbert), 1953-1957 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Morawetz, Cathleen (and Herbert), 1965-1969 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Morawetz, Oskar, 1955 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Morrey, Charles B., Jr., 1950 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Morrey, Charles B., Jr., 1951, 1958 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Morrison, Philip--"The Laboratory Demobilizes", 1946 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Morse, Marston, 1942-1959 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Morse, Marston, 1962-1963 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Morse, Marston--"Relations Between the Critical Points of a Real Function of Independent Variables", 1925 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Morse, Marston--Six Lectures, 1932 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Morse, Marston--Zurich Lecture--"The Calculus of Variations in the Large", 1932 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Moser, Jurgen, 1961-1969 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Moulton, F.J., 1940-1941 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Muller, Claus, 1952-1958 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Muller, Claus, 1961-1964 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Muller, Erwin, 1950-1951 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Munk, Walter H., 1947-1950 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Murray, Ruth, 1962-1964 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Muskhelishvili, N.I. (see "Russian Mathematicians"), 1962-1963 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - "N" Misc., 1939-1969 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Nachbin, Leopoldo, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Nadai, A., 1943-1945 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Nakoinz, Ilona, 1966-1967 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1941-1960 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - National Academy of Sciences (1 of 2), 1962-1964, undated (Box 65, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence and nominee bios
    - National Academy of Sciences (2 of 2), 1962-1964, undated (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - National Academy of Sciences (1 of 2), 1965-1973 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - National Academy of Sciences (2 of 2), 1965-1973 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - National Academy of Sciences], 1968-1971 (Box 65, Folder 14)
      Includes materials on Academy's position on dysgenics and genetic reproductive issues
    - National Academy of Sciences--Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, 1961-1963 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, 1966-1968 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, 1969-1970 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, circa 1970-1971 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - National Academy of Sciences--General, 1971-1972 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - National Academy of Sciences--Nomination of Peter Lax and Fritz John, 1962-1966 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - National Academy of Sciences--USSR & Eastern Europe (1 of 2), 1962-1968 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - National Academy of Sciences--USSR & Eastern Europe (2 of 2), 1962-1968 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - National Bureau of Standards, 1943-1950 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - National Bureau of Standards, 1954-1959 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - National Computing Center, 1966-1967 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - "A National Institute for Advanced Instruction in Basic and Applied Sciences," Memo Concerning, undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - National Research Council, 1952-1954 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - National Research Council--Proceedings of a Conference on Training in Applied Mathematics, 1953 October (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - National Science Foundation, 1941-1955 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - National Science Foundation, 1956-1960 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - National Science Foundation (1 of 3), 1958-1960 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - National Science Foundation (2 of 3), 1958-1960 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - National Science Foundation (3 of 3), 1958-1960 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - National Science Foundation (1 of 2), 1961-1966 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - National Science Foundation (2 of 2), 1961-1966 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - National Science Foundation (1 of 2), 1966-1971 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - National Science Foundation (2 of 2), 1966-1971 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - National Science Foundation--Contract, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - National Science Foundation--Director of Scientific Personnel and Education, 1959-1961 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - National Science Foundation--Grant, 1966-1968 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - National Science Foundation--Nominations (1 of 2), 1960 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - National Science Foundation--Nominations (2 of 2), 1960 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - National Science Foundation--Proposals, 1961 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - National Science Foundation--Science Development Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - National Science Foundation--University Computing Facilities, 1955-1956 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - National Science Foundation--Washington University, 1958-1959 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - National Security Research Initiation Laboratory, undated (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Natuurkundig Laboratorium der N.V. Philips' Gloeilampenfabrieken, 1929-1931 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - "Naturwissenschaftliche Forschung in den USA", 1961 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Naval Ordinance Laboratory, 1948-1950 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Navy (Administrative Circulars), 1945-1946 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Navy Department of Research--General, 1948-1951 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Navy Office of Inspector of Naval Material, 1950 (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Netherlands Academy of Sciences, 1958 (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Neugebauer, Otto, 1938-1953 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Neugebauer, Otto--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1926 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1961-1963 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1964 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1965-1967 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - New York University--General, 1934-1961 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - New York University--General (1 of 2), 1961-1966 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - New York University--General (2 of 2), 1961-1966 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - New York University--General (1 of 2), 1964-1971 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - New York University--General (2 of 2), 1964-1971 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - New York University--Engineering School, 1950-1958 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - New York University--Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1958-1963 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - New York University Institute of Space Sciences, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - New York University--Physics Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - New York University--Physics Committee, 1961 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Newsom, Carroll V., 1961-1963 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Neyman, J., 1952-1954 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Nichols, Joseph B., 1948-1949 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Nickel, K., 1962 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Nielson, Jakob, 1946-1950, undated (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Nielson, Jakob, 1947-1957 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Nirenberg, Louis, 1954-1958, undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Nirenberg, Louis, 1961-1965 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Nirenberg, Louis--"Linear Operators and Their Spectra with Applications to Quantum Mechanics", undated (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Nirenberg, Louis--"On Elliptic Partial Differential Equations", 1959 (Box 70, Folder 12)